Hello, hello, good evening everyone.
Hello, hello, hello everyone.
Good evening everyone, thank you for coming to watch our live broadcast on the day before the National Day.
Good evening everyone, hello, hello, can everyone hear us?
This is Xue Li and Mr. Jeffy.
Hello, hello, can you hear me?
Okay, very energetic.
Okay, okay, hello everyone.
Hello everyone, I am Sherry from Marvelous Designer.
And today, our official live broadcast room of Marvelous Designer,
fortunately, Mr. Jeffy is here again to give you today's live class.
Mr. Jeffy, say hello to everyone.
Hello, hello, hello everyone, I am Mr. Jeffy.
Okay.
That was a very short self-introduction.
No, because Mr. Jeffy has also come to our live broadcast room before.
Everyone really likes Mr. Jeffy's works.
We also often interact with Mr. Jeffy.
Mr. Jeffy also opened his own Bilibili account this year, right?
Yes, that's right.
I only started to post things this year.
I used to only watch, not post.
Then why don't we let Mr. Jeffy start here first?
We started with Mr. Jeffy's part,
and then after Mr. Jeffy's part is over,
it will be my part to show everyone.
So let's welcome Mr. Jeffy first.
Welcome Mr. Jeffy.
Okay, okay.
Thank you.
This part is mainly to tell everyone
that in my course,
we usually encounter some problems.
But it may not be some specific problems,
but some solutions.
I just want to give everyone a chance
to raise some solutions.
In fact, the problem we encounter is that
the costumes we made with MD,
the effect we made,
may not match the effect we want.
It's just that you know what you want,
but you can't get it out.
And then there are some things that he made,
but it may not look good.
It's just that he took it out in a big way,
but it doesn't look good.
So I'm going to deal with these two questions.
I think everyone may be
not fully understanding the analysis of this costume.
So I'm going to talk to everyone here
about the content of the costume collection analysis.
Then I will briefly summarize here.
In the case of costume collection analysis,
in general,
it can actually be divided into many categories.
Then I simply summarized it myself.
It is divided into four types.
The first type is here.
It's the single-point collection.
Then it's vertical, right?
It's only affected by gravity.
And one point is the collection.
There are also two points of collection.
It includes a vertical between two points
and a vertical of a single point.
This is the extension of the first type.
Then the third type.
It is a single-point collection
plus some compression.
The compression of Gumi Shiki is that
it is affected by other objects
or other external forces.
This will produce a compression
of a shape like XYZ.
It will especially appear in our
Let me show you first.
Some of the ankles here
and some of the wrists
will be compressed.
In fact, they are all related to this kind of compression.
Gumi Shiki compression.
Then there is also a kind of stretch.
Stretch,
let me see.
It's not here yet.
But you can see this picture.
You should understand.
It's equivalent to between two points.
It's the opposite of a collection direction.
There will be a stretch of a compression.
Through these four collection methods,
we can make an absolute part of a compression.
Then why do we use some of these here?
We use some of the drawing materials
to show you,
not the real costume.
Because the drawing thing is actually
a drawing artist.
He has a concept and a formula
of this kind of costume.
In this way,
we can be more clear and clear.
You can see it at a glance.
What kind of curse is it?
What kind of collection method is it?
Let me take a look at it first.
Here is one.
Right?
It's the same chicken.
It's a thigh.
Right?
Then squeeze it here.
Then come down.
Then the outer circle is the costume.
Right?
This is a way of squeezing.
Then here,
we are in this part.
It's a stretch.
Right?
There is also a little bit of a heavy compression.
This is a stretch plus compression.
It's a combination of two kinds.
Then like our sleeve.
Look here.
It also shows that it is a single point.
Right?
If it's a single point,
we come down.
It's a pure feeling.
Then here,
we have a called
It's also a compression.
We got a
It's a sleeve,
a sleeve,
and then a compression.
It's a curse.
Other words,
we can take a look at it.
For example,
this place,
right?
It's a single point.
Right?
There's a little compression here.
Then this place.
It's a little bit like this.
The feeling of double-pointing.
From here to here.
Right?
It's a feeling of double-pointing.
Then there's a little compression here.
Right?
So we look at these things.
It can be completely calculated from these four types.
That is to say,
if you say,
for example,
my own one.
For example,
make a dress.
I do mine.
For example,
this dress.
He.
For example,
it feels like this.
If it doesn't come out,
it may be needed.
Uh,
some,
that is,
the force on the weight is strengthened.
Whether it's through the change.
The density of the material is also good.
Or through,
uh,
use our point to stretch.
It's good.
Then it must be.
It's not strong enough.
So that's why it's like this.
Uh,
uh,
the fold can't appear.
Of course,
it has something to do with the shape.
Ah,
because the shape,
it has to be long enough.
The shape,
Then it can be folded up.
Right?
And then,
like this,
here,
some of the vertical conditions here.
He actually received a pressure from up and down.
So he's going to have a little bit of a mess like this.
Ah,
the pressure on the top.
That is to say,
this place is very likely to be a double layer.
He was hit.
There are about four directions in front and back.
Then he will appear on the board.
Some irregular one.
This is also a kind of pressure.
Ah,
so,
uh,
learn this.
Strength analysis.
Ah,
it's a very important thing for me to be able to make an analysis.
And then we know the basic theory now.
Let's take a look at some more practical cases.
Ah,
practical case.
First of all,
it's some,
uh,
some of our 3A four-generation games.
Some production.
How is their clothing made?
Ah,
first of all,
this is a card line.
Ah,
you don't know if it's MD.
it's a carving or a card line.
Ah,
it's all about being in line with him.
For example,
our ankles are here,
right?
We often have some gravity,
So there will be some compression here.
And then,
but because his clothes are not wide enough,
so he is more intimate.
So he won't have one down.
It's one person,
one person like this,
like a dress.
A,
uh,
curse.
Ah,
so if you have a person here,
this kind of curse like a dress,
it means that you may be too wide on this board.
Like here,
he will have a very obvious compression,
ah,
like a compression on this side.
And then,
he is more empty here,
and then here is more dense.
He has a dense comparison,
so this is his main,
uh,
I want to make this kind of force,
this kind of feeling,
it must be,
right?
You can use his strength.
Ah,
we can push his board back.
This width is wider,
right?
In this way,
here,
you can create a feeling of compression.
Okay,
then these are some of the games.
Ah,
this should be a scan.
The case of the game,
like this,
it should be a mysterious sea.
If it's a mysterious sea,
here,
there are also a lot of this kind of compression,
compression caused by the rhythm,
uh,
and then there are a lot of stretching here.
A curse,
right?
So,
if you want to do something like this,
a curse type,
then,
you must know that he must be this end and this end.
A compression is made,
so your sleeves will be a little longer,
and you have to fix this point,
then,
in the middle of this section,
there will be a compression,
so this section of the curse will be made for him very easily.
Ah,
but here,
it's also behind,
that is,
his clothes have to be long,
and then this place,
fix it,
ah,
and then the curse in this place will come out,
and then we take a look at this three-country thing,
ah,
three countries,
this sleeve,
you can take a look,
ah,
a little bit bigger,
this case of three countries,
ah,
you can take a look,
his place is also a lot of compression,
first of all,
the sleeve should be long enough,
right,
but you can't see too much on his sleeve,
he is affected by gravity,
for example,
he won't,
he is very little in this direction,
right,
this direction is very little,
then,
in fact,
it means that his fabric may be relatively light,
so,
his,
ah,
in the direction of gravity,
he will be relatively small,
so we can see that when we calculate in MD,
for example,
we want to make this sleeve,
then we will give a relatively light fabric,
right,
then,
let's take a look at others,
ah,
others,
I think I made some better game cases,
for example,
cyberpunk,
ah,
his sleeve,
the same,
ah,
here is also the compression of the fold,
which means that the length of his lower half will be relatively long,
the board will be relatively long,
ah,
how long,
his length will depend on his fold,
a play level,
ah,
then this sleeve is also,
he will be more suitable,
come to this position,
but he doesn't,
he puts the finger on it,
then it will produce compression here,
then you can do it here,
you must make a long sleeve,
and then after making a long sleeve,
he will produce a compression of a fold here,
right,
but these folds are all the same,
including this,
this is equivalent to our single point of the hammer,
the hammer,
that is to say,
the fabric of this place will be relatively thicker,
ah,
it will be thicker,
so it will produce such a fold,
that is,
look at some reference pictures,
ah,
for example,
these reference pictures,
we can use some,
ah,
受力的分析来力推出它的面料,
到底应该是采用一个什么样的面料,
会才能造成出这样的一个褶皱效果,
对吧,
所以说受力分析这一点是非常重要的,
然后我们的板片也是,
啊,
我们板片,
比如说这个地方褶皱,
如果说你褶皱过长,
他的裤子可能会是这样,
但是他呢,
他裤子的这个左边这个轮廓,
啊,
然后它是这样的一个轮廓,
对吧,
这个轮廓,
所以说你裤子多长,
就通过他的这个褶皱受力分析,
我们大概就可以知道,
如果我们要给他做差不多的裤子,
然后我们的裤子需要做到多长,
啊,
就大概会知道,
然后放大给大家看,
给你们说要放大看一下,
嗯,
就在后面,
Then go to aim
In this case, in fact, because of everyone's body type,
including you to count to each person's body,
the length of his clothes is different.
So I suggest that you
do an analysis of him like me
and then deduce the appearance and length of his whole board.
Then someone asked if MD was calculated
MD, of course, can be calculated
After calculating, we will fix it
That is to say, the purpose of the repair is to make it look better
Then we will talk about how to fix it in detail later
But MD is very efficient
and can do the whole board as quickly as possible at the first time
So if you want to imitate a feeling like this
But we don't mean to do the same thing for him
Just to imitate the texture of a cloth like this
is the texture of 3A game cloth
We can use this method to analyze them
Then include some cartoon types
That's the most important thing
The most important thing is to make the card look like this
He is a very popular cyborg, right?
With the edge of ranger
Actually, he's drawing the cloth
It's also based on a normal force direction
For example, he bend his arm, right?
This place has a force of an only 2
very obvious
right
and also here
he also has such a force of one
then plays because the sleeves are too long
For example, you see a like this
In a Zhezhou type
You may need to be clear
This is a Zhezhou caused by an only one
Including this one is also an only one
And his sleeves can see that the level of shrinkage is relatively high
So its sleeves are very long
You pull it long and the sleeves will probably come here
That is, if you want to do this kind of sleeve
So its
The
vertical analysis is probably like this
Then what about the short sleeve and short pants
The short sleeve and short pants are the same
The short sleeve and short pants are also
An analysis of its
Real cloth and clothing
Its basic strength
It doesn't say it's too
Too much to drag out our regular
The range of common sense
Except for some special animations
Like some of the things you usually see
Things like cats and mice
It will have some body or behavior
Some large extensions and changes
Exaggerated performance
But for the most part
We can actually use the same
A set of hand-picked analysis theories
To put the whole clothing pattern
And then the fabric of the fabric
Then the clothing style
These things are pushed out for him
And then let's take a look at
It's a real clothing
Real clothing
Its real clothing is relative to our previous
For example, one of our four generations
A character or two-dimensional cartoon
Or its foldable details will be more complicated
More complicated
And it's going to be more complex
There are various aspects of the process
But in general
We can still do this kind of regulation
For example, in this place
We have so many
A foldable fold, right
We have so many foldable folds
Why
Because of this board
A little wider
And then there's a compression force in the middle
So it will produce some foldable folds
So when we're doing the back of this board
When it's broken
You have to make it a little wider
Make it a little wider
And then they will
There will be some foldable folds in the middle
Like this one
This one
It's some of us
Some of these horizontal folds
Right
Some of the horizontal compression folds
If you squeeze the fold
We need to make this thing a little longer
And then make the sleeve a little longer
And then I'm going to lift it up
After you lift the whole thing up
We're going to have some here
Some of the horizontal compression folds
The compression fold is through the board shape
And then he did an analysis
And then here
Here, it's just a few simple folds
Just a few folds
If it's a fold
We can see that there are a lot of vertical folds
The whole board shape may be a little longer
We sew it from this part to this part
Right
It will have some vertical folds
well
And then
The chest
The chest is what I teach
That's where people ask a lot of questions
Why can't I do it in the village
It's just the effect of my logic tower
It's also because it's probably because it's not long enough
It's a lot of vertical folds
In fact, it's very long
And then I got a pressure from left and right
Right
And then it can be a
There are a lot of vertical folds like this
And then we have this one above
This village, this board
In fact, it's in the middle direction
The middle direction is actually not too long
Not too long
The middle direction is just right
It's mainly his
This one
The horizontal will be a little longer
So this side will be squeezed
So when we look at this costume
When making this version
We can make this horizontal a little bit longer
Ah
It's not a recording
I'm in this
Let me take a look
A costume like this
For example, we want to make such a dynamic
It's a little bit more dynamic
In fact, the previous costumes were more static
More dynamic costumes
His one
This one is also the same
You can also use the formula of my previous four
Here is a squeeze
Right
And then here is a little bit of a stretch between the two points
So everyone
If you can't get this one out
We can put a little bit of a point here
Then pull it down a little bit
Put a point here
Pull it up a little bit
Right
His overall stretch is coming out
And then this one from here to here
You have to give enough width
So in this case
This piece of folding can be successfully calculated
Ah
Then about this one behind us
Behind this piece
He has such a fold
In fact, it is very similar to our one
A fold with two points
Right
It's very similar to the fold analysis in front of us
Such a fold with two points
The fold is always the first
Is to give enough
The density of the material
Right
The density is big enough
It will fall down in the middle
Then next
Is to give a length of enough panels
Then it will fold in the middle
Right
So if you don't come out
Can't do it
It's just two points
One is that the panels are not done well
The second is that the fold analysis is not done well
well
Okay
Then we look at some more simple modern decorations
More simple modern decorations
Like this
It's very simple
A point of gain
Right
Then there are some stacks here
So how many stacks
Right
If you want to stack
If it's as dense as it is
Then our sleeves
Should it be done
Like about this long
Right
Then are we in this place?
If you want to make a fold
Then the fold in this place
Can be successfully made
Then include some of our front sides
This kind of vertical fold
Vertical fold
We can just put the whole panel
Make it a little longer
A little longer on the horizontal
If it's a little longer
Then something a little longer
We squeeze it in the middle
Just squeeze it in the middle
We will have such a vertical fold
It's actually a squeeze
Like this
Okay
Then the rest
Let's take my own example
Some of the clothes I made myself
For example, like this fan
Make it a little bigger
This fan
For example, this place
It also has some squeeze folds
Right
Then there are two shoulder straps here
It's a fold with a single point of gravity
And then here are some
Folding and squeeze folds
Its sleeves should actually be longer
I just put it in on purpose
I cut it off
Then there will be some squeeze folds
Then we do it like this
Then include the following
A fold of this movement
That's also because this panel is long
But then our waist is also thinner
Right
So if you wear this
It will have a force of the left and right squeeze
Then add a force to it
Right
It will produce such a fold
So if we want to make a fold
It must be an analysis of its training situation
According to the training situation of your reference picture
After that
Then to push the length of a panel
Then find a balance between these two
And then including Lolita
This set is also
Lolita
A lot of people think
This set in the middle
It's not easy to do this little thing in the middle
For example, this piece in the middle
This piece in the middle
This piece
In fact, it is also a
Right
A horizontal squeeze
In the middle
This piece is a very long piece of cloth
We sewed a very short frame
Then there will naturally be some of this kind of fold in the middle
Right
Then the skirt is also a very long skirt
Sewed to a very short and thin waist
Then this place will naturally produce some of this kind of center fold
Then include the shoulder
The shoulder is also a one-way one-way one-way
I won't say much about this
This is very simple
Okay
Then so to speak
This受力分析
I hope that is to say that this受力分析
This four
Four受力分析
Everybody must be very good at grasping it
Just understand it
Just understand
For example, the four of our受力
What is it like
And then where will it show up
And then after showing up in this place
So if I want to do
A wrinkle in this place
Then I have to consider its state of受力
If you make a wrinkle
If it's different from the wrinkle you want
Then it's definitely your受力
Not quite right
The reason for the wrong受力 is that?
Where is it?
It may be the length of your board,
or the board is long or short, right?
Then the board is long or short,
you can look at it according to your reference picture,
whether it is long or short, right?
Then in this way,
you can modify the shape of your costume.
Then the second part,
and then there are some things that many people are asking,
is that when many people are making clothes,
he or she will not adjust a variable parameter,
and he or she is not good at the application of the level.
Then I will talk about these two things first.
The first one is the level.
You can see that I am making this yellow suit now.
This yellow suit,
this yellow suit,
when it is finalized,
all the objects do not open any level.
The layer is 0,
but when I am computing,
it must be for him or her.
The result is once defined,
but after the calculation is complete,
I will turn off his or her results.
In this way,
it will reduce the occurrence of some cross-examination problems.
Then many students,
when he or she is doing it,
that is to say,
we turn on the results,
and then let him or she keep turning it on.
In this way,
for those who are competing,
for those who are doing this kind of competitive costume,
in fact, I think it is not very good.
It is best for everyone to say that
to maintain a habit when doing some static costumes.
That is,
after the results are used,
then calculate what you want,
what you want,
then the first time you need to turn off this thing.
I really have a lot of people ask me why this kind of bug will appear.
In fact, I see it all because of the results they open.
In fact,
so this point,
I hope everyone can pay attention to it when making their own costumes.
Then there is another point,
that is to say,
our one material material parameters,
material material parameters,
in fact,
in this MD official channel,
MD official channel,
basically every video I have watched,
it is the kind that does not jump from beginning to end,
because the content he talks about is really very comprehensive,
and it is also very good,
and it can be used very well.
Then I also like this way of talking about him very much.
So at this point,
I will give you an introduction that is too much.
In fact, the parameters are probably these,
probably these are not many,
so the previous one,
this parameter,
we first three,
ah,
three three three three in a group of a total of four groups,
the first 12 in a total of four groups,
and then the three behind are single parameters.
So in the md official channel,
he will have a specific parameter introduction,
ah,
the first three is the elasticity,
and this is a degree of bend,
so I will not go into too much detail here,
I suggest everyone to go to the MD official channel,
and take a look at what we talked about earlier,
what are some of its detailed parameters, right?
Then if you spray it, yes, this is a group of voices.
This is a group of voices.
The group of voices looks like this.
The group of voices is actually for this place.
It's easier to stand up, right? It's easier to stand up.
Then this is a lot of things at that time.
Then there is another one.
Everyone in this group asked me.
You asked me how to do it.
In fact, there is still a video in the MD official channel.
That is to say, you can go and see it.
It's really very detailed.
It's not more detailed than I'm talking about here for a few minutes.
So you can recommend it.
And then I'm here.
It seems to be a year or two ago.
And then I made this one.
What is this called?
What is the shape of Bai Zhe?
What kind of things can be done in MD?
Then I will give you a demonstration here.
Probably one is like this, right?
It's a little bit like the skirt of that kind of JK.
Then there are some of these two groups.
Two groups, right?
Then I will do a calculation and classification.
There is also this one.
He is.
I don't really know how to say this professional name.
Anyway, there are so many kinds of shapes.
Then you can save this picture.
Then what do you want yourself?
Then you can adjust it according to the parameters here.
And then how to adjust it specifically?
You can take a look at the official MD official one.
A video of Bai Zhe.
This is really something that has been posted.
Have posted.
Okay.
And then.
I also want to tell you a part that I am more interested in.
It's about the production of this child.
In fact, the production of the material,
one of the main applications I use here is this SD.
SD, then my sticker is basically a basic.
Basically, it's all SD output.
Some of this.
Some of the sticker texture of Tai Ling.
Sticker texture.
And then these are attached to one of our fabrics.
It will.
To him.
Some changes.
For example.
This place.
Metal.
And then the roughness.
The hair line.
Such a change.
And then you can make the surface texture of this clothing look more.
There are layers.
More real.
Okay.
And then this software.
If I do it.
It's mainly.
The application is to do some small elements.
For example.
Like this one.
Right.
It's a little bit.
A small element.
Including this.
A shiny stripe.
Including some of these inside.
Some of the little gold.
Then his.
In fact, the material properties.
The two are different.
The material properties.
The quality is different.
Then in general.
I don't see the.
If you apply it.
Then it will produce one.
A relatively.
A rich.
A material effect.
For example, like this.
A relatively.
Rich one.
Material effect.
For example.
For example, the texture here is different from the texture here, right?
In this way, you will have a rich and different texture effect.
Then, this software is very easy to use with MD.
Because MD can make a very good UV by itself.
I have a bad arrangement for UV.
Then, if this material ball is put directly on it,
then it can get the appearance I want.
So, this side can reduce a lot of our top and UV work.
So, this UV function is also mentioned in the MD official channel.
Please take a look at it.
Then, about the material,
actually, you can see that the way I output the sticker here
is actually different from the final appearance.
That's because I'm all in
my rendering software.
I use a Blender.
Then, a rendering is done in it.
Then, the rendering comes out.
Then, some toning is done.
Then, it reaches a color that I think is suitable.
Then, it includes some images.
This texture is all done for it in this SD.
Then, apply it to it.
It looks like this.
About the introduction of the material,
there are probably these.
Then, this software,
in fact, it is not like some conventional software.
It is a node-based software.
So, it may be more complicated to learn.
I suggest you to study it first.
Then, I want to share with you some art-related problems.
This is my summary.
There are probably a few points.
Although it is not complete,
I think there are a few more important points for everyone to summarize.
One is the first one.
We have some students.
When they are doing it,
it may be a triangular surface
or some four-sided surfaces with MD.
This is how it is used directly.
In this case, it is actually no problem in the distance.
But if we look closely, it will be like this.
There will be some of this, right?
Something like this.
Of course, if you don't do special writing,
it doesn't matter.
You can't see it.
But if you want to do some special writing like this,
I think you should try to avoid such a phenomenon.
So, I suggest that you still say that
it is necessary to do it well.
Do it well.
Then, we have a whole curse.
Including some of what we did.
For example, some of these costumes have some curses.
And some of our costumes.
And some of our designs.
In fact, all the models,
they are all light and shadow.
So, its purpose is to divide the light and shadow.
So, what is the purpose of dividing the light and shadow?
It is also to be able to
make a selection of this whole picture.
For example, let's take this dress.
If we do a lot of a curse on the back like this, right?
We do more curses.
After doing more,
we do less curses in this place.
We deliberately do less.
Then, our sight is easy to be concentrated on its upper body.
Then, this description comparison can guide very well.
That is to say,
that is to say,
a focus of your work,
a focus of your work.
This is one.
So, we think that
when we do the curse ourselves,
we must pay attention to this light and shadow collection.
And the comparison of the description.
Because we generally say that
we do some curses.
For example, we want to do this kind of curse.
We can't make it the same.
So, we will still take some
important places.
For example, there will be more curses in this place.
There may not be so many curses in this place.
Right?
That is to say,
we probably do it in the direction of such a reference.
In this case,
we can make a curse that you think is good.
Because in the end,
it will be influenced by the light and shadow.
Right?
If you make a curse,
there will be a light and shadow effect.
There will be a light and shadow effect.
There will be a brush effect.
Right?
Okay.
Then,
I'll give you some of the following.
I still found some painting cases.
Why did I find painting cases?
Because painting cases
are all some very good artists.
Then they control their own screen.
A logic is fully expressed in his screen.
So, if here,
because we finally make clothes or do something,
our final output form is nothing but a jpg, right?
Jpg.
Then there is mt4.
Only these two formats.
These two formats are the current ones.
We throw away the hand carving and don't talk about it.
Just two formats.
Then it actually represents a two-dimensional picture on the computer.
Then if it's a picture,
how do we arrange his costume curse
to make it look better?
Right?
First of all,
we also need some description to compare the curse.
For example, I really like this painting.
Right?
Then here,
his curse will be very close to this place.
This place will be very close.
It will be very comfortable.
Then here is his whole person.
The whole person.
He is from top to bottom.
There is a trend from book to pen.
A trend from book to pen.
So in general,
he will have a lot of
immediate curse in the dark.
Then in his bright side,
he actually did some more complete highlights.
Then in this case,
his performance form is like this.
For example, if I just want to do a cool pose like this,
right?
But what we can do
is not his clothes.
It may not be his character,
but we like his artistic style.
Then when we make clothes,
we must pay attention
to the trend from top to bottom,
from book to pen.
Then we can make it like him.
In the dark,
there are so many details.
Right?
There are many details,
including here.
Then the bright side is a whole piece of border light.
Then the whole feeling is a very cool pose.
Then this feeling will come out.
Then include some,
for example,
we count the cartoon in the second round.
There is also a certain number of comparisons throughout.
For example,
in fact,
he won't do too much of a curse.
You can see that there are very few of them.
His overall secret is in his hair.
The engraving of the hair
is the most detailed part of his whole picture.
So we do the curse.
In fact,
it doesn't necessarily have to do this curse.
How rich and real is it?
Right?
We compare this thing with the book.
Then when we make clothes,
we want to do this cartoon character,
it is not recommended to make this kind of very powerful,
very powerful,
a curse.
We try to put a powerful part of the picture in,
for example,
his eyes,
his eyelashes,
his eyelashes can be very thin.
You can see that he has drawn out every one of these eyelashes,
including the hair on this side.
The other side is strong,
and then the clothes,
we deliberately do it to make it more comfortable.
In this case,
we can achieve an effect like him.
So these things,
including this,
this is also his clothes.
In general,
we will not do too much curse.
everyone's hair will do a comparison.
Then we actually through a dense relationship,
that is,
our entire picture's dense relationship is expressed through clothing.
Then there is one,
that is,
through light and shadow,
because the light and shadow,
according to our curse,
he will have a dense change,
right?
For example,
this painting,
his brightest place is his chest.
This piece,
for example,
is the part that everyone wants you to look at.
He will do a comparison,
right?
The brightness will be relatively high,
and then this is the face,
right?
Then this is his very cool one,
a light of a shadow.
Then the brightest place,
the brightest place of the whole picture,
must be the place where the author wants to lead you to watch.
Then,
so to speak,
in these three works,
the curse of his clothing
plays a role in enriching the details of the dark part,
right?
There is another one,
that is to say,
enrich the whole picture.
The real texture plays a role.
In this,
in fact,
we are rich in a detail of his gray part,
right?
There are about one,
two,
and about three layers of gray here,
but the hair is one,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
there are a lot,
right?
Like this curse,
this curse is basically a piece,
there is no big curse,
he just used a few lines to show the real texture of his clothing,
that is to say,
our whole picture,
let's do the clothing,
that is to say,
everyone will definitely find some of their favorite pictures,
ah,
to do a,
machine,
of us to do a reference production,
so about his custom style,
his style,
what his art performance is like.
Ah,
that is to say,
that's why I have to use a method like mine to analyze him,
his clairvoyance,
and his whole plot,
for example,
this place costume,
ah,
he deliberately here is a foot,
it doesn't mean that he is a real costume,
there must be a foot here,
and he can delseshuri or something in the back,
right.
He is satisficated with the shape of this view in this corner,
so what we are doing in the costume,
for example,
we have seen some references,
ah,
Look at some reference pictures.
That is, I like this kind of wrinkle,
but you don't have to make such a costume,
and you don't have to make such a resume.
So we can put some of the things that we have not made yet,
that is to say, things related to art,
and some of the reality of us.
The瘦力分析以及瘦力分析以及它版片的分析结合起来
然后我们不论是做这种卡通风格也好
还是做一些写实风格也好
那么它的褶皱和服装的制作表现都不会差
然后服装还有一点一些作用
就是它能够功夫角色的剪影
加强角色整个画面张力
以及对于角色本身定位能有一个阐述
因为其实我们经常在做角色的时候
其实制作服装是一个非常重要的一个环节
因为它一个角色的服装造型
比如说它的服装它的装它的发型
它的动作
能够很好的体现这个角色的性格以及所属的场景
而它的脸部对吧
有多少的细节
包括它的身材或者怎么样的
对吧
其实都没有那么的重要
所以说服装为什么重要
就是因为这个地方
它能够让整个角色整个画面的一个张力进行加强
比如说我们这个衣服
真实的衣服其实是没有这么飘上去的
对吧
我们故意把服装做的哎
这么一飘对吧
就感觉整个画面就简易扩开了
如果说我们把这两边住啊
那边挡住就感觉有点临庭无奇
不太配不太配搭它这个比较嚣张的一个表情啊
所以说我们在进行一个服装的制作的时候啊
也一定要考虑到呃就是说我们制作一个角色
它是一个什么样的性格
它的服装的话
我们需要做成一个什么样的一个造型
能够更好的体现这个服装的性格
并且增强一个画面的张力
啊
所以说这个用服装制作
所以说服装是非常重要的一个部分啊
包括这个也是啊
这个也是这整个有一个这样的一个弯曲的走向
感觉这边好像我们做了一个什么东西一样
对吧
那么它也是通过一个服装的制作啊
服装来够引导这整个画面的一个表现力啊
当然它动作也是非常有张力啊
这个动作我们这次先不说
我们先说在这个特定的有张力的动作下啊
这个服装我们应该怎么样子制作
才能够表现出它一个
这个画面的一个画面感
然后这个呢就呃这一点这张我也很喜欢啊
它也是能够呃能够比较体现它整个角色的一个艺术氛围吧
其实它是服装做的很大
你可以看到啊
做的很大
比如说它剪影衣服
你可以看到这个衣服的袖口的长度
跟它跨的长度是一样差不多了
啊
整个人的话它其实就是一个对吧
由宽到窄的一个这个样子梯形的一个形状
那么这个剪影就会比较夸张啊
就是属于一个
一个比较偏卡通的一个范畴了
就是说大家在那么在在在做一些卡通的服装的时候啊
大家也可以适当的啊
运用系到一些我们的这种美术的这个剪影的方法
那么褶皱的话也是啊
它受力褶皱其实也是符合现实规律的
比如说这地方褶皱对吧
这种褶皱其实它跟我们这个地方几家褶皱啊
刚才讲的受力分析其实没什么区别
所以说它的物理规则其实是相似的啊
只不过通过它
做服装的一些张力剪影啊
这些东西够更好的
你看这个角色你想表达的一个感受
像这个也是啊
这个的话它能够很好的体现这个角色的一个弧度
像一般的裙子它这个地方如果说你真正做的话
它这样不会翘起来
这个地方会这样子下去对吧
它故意这么画来翘起来
也是为了在这个地方的点影啊
能够更加的向外扩啊对吧
能够更加向外扩
包括这里也是啊
这里能够更加向外扩
它故意这么做的
包括这边也是对吧
包括这里也是
所以说呢这些东西呢
就是大家在具体制作的时候
当我们解决到就是褶皱怎么出的问题的时候
那么在解决我们整个画面怎么好看的时候
就需要大家对就是使用我们的一些呃软件MD啊
来进行这个服装的一些调整
它不一定是真实的
但是呢一定是合理的啊
然后还有一个呢
其实一些在服装制作上面啊
能够很好的表达出一个角色的所属的环境
是那个比如说这个这个人画啊
就像一个扇板一个祭祀对吧
然后呢他也比较的针对来说比较现代啊
比如背个这样的挎包对吧
然后穿一个相对现代一点的鞋子
人家跟这个就比较现代了对吧
然后他整个服装呢
他是一个对吧
这样的一个剪影一个这样的剪影
那整个裙摆会这么飘荡起来
这样的话我们做出来的话会感觉这个角色比较的活
就是比较的
像一个呃怎么说呢
就是他这他会给予一些动态
这服装的一些动态
然后来体现这整个服装的整个角色的一个剪影的一个外貌啊
这个很像一个感觉跟个蘑菇差不多啊
还能画那么多蘑菇
把这蘑菇就跟这蘑菇差不多
你看他就是一个蘑菇啊
就是个蘑菇
然后包括这些服装上的一些纹路啊
能够很好的表现出这个角色是个什么职业
对吧
就说我们在制作服装的话
这一个角色是非常重要的
然后他的脸的话其实就不是那么重要
我个人觉得啊
就是服装
发型
妆容
道具场景
这些是体现一个角色的非常重要的一个点啊
ok
然后下面的也是一些啊
上面一些就
就
不一一给大家演示了
啊一样的
他们在服装这个地方会啊
有一些剪影的一些变化对吧
然后会这样服装飘起来啊
有一些画面的张力
然后这个也是啊
这个也是
据说一副好的作品啊
大家想做一些
呃好的作品
然后视觉看起来比较
漂亮的作品啊
就是一定要考虑
前面我说的这几点啊
破谱光影
疏密剪影张力
颜色描述啊
然后考虑我们因为我们是只做
cg嘛对吧
只做 cg的话
我们就只用考虑成一个jpg或mp4的一个形式
然后呢
呃所以说我觉得大家如果说是刚刚接触这个行业
或者说是在这个行业想进行一些提高的话
我觉得通过制作服装真的是能让你们收获到非常多的一个东西啊
就比如说我通过md来制作一些啊
我不做脸对吧
我不做头发
我就把他衣服做好
那么你可以说能够学到比如说角色的一些啊
剪影张力
然后然后比如说学到一些疏密的一些安排对吧
因为呢一个服装的话
他是一个角色
他其实百分之九十百分之八十都是靠服装撑起来
他不可能不穿衣服对吧
他肯定要穿衣服
我们也不是搞那种呃不在那种呃什么人体艺术对吧
我们做的是一些商业美术
大家现在都比较喜欢一些商业美术
把商业美术的话
那么一定就是说他肯定需要表现出通过服装来表现出他的一个整体的画面的一个疏密质感
这点是非常多的艺术家进行一个运用的一个方式啊
所以说我们通过制作服装就可以学到很多一些呃优秀的艺术家优秀的画师他们的一些想法
然后呢我们在做自己的作品的时候呢就可以把这些呃想法呢
呃想法能够冲入冲入进去
然后能够提升自己产品自己的快提升自己自己作品的一个质量啊
然后呃但是这个就是说我们所制作的一个cg还有还有一些就是美术啊
其实呢都其实比较偏向于一些真实物理的
我你啊就是比较偏向于一些摄影
其实我们现在很多渲染器渲染软件啊
他都其实是模拟的一个
真实的
拍摄拍照的一个技法
然后呢再加上一些啊比如说绘画里面的像我刚才讲的光影书面剪影这些知识啊来一个结合性的产物所以说呢
我觉得大家在做一些服装的时候啊就是不要过于的
纠结啊
规规的纠结就是一定要和这个参考图住的一模一样啊
这一点是呃如果说一定要最后这个的话是很难受的一件事情
所以说就像我刚才说的啊大家可以通过他
大家可以通过他的一个受力分析
也通过他的一个光影书题就是书密
光影载体书密表现一些剪影
然后呢能大概推导出啊这一块褶皱密集这一块褶皱比较稀疏对吧
这一块褶皱是两点受力这一块褶皱有拉伸
对吧
只要说你这些地方都还原好了
那么就是那么他的真实程度就会大差不差
就不会是做的呃非常的假
所以说呢
大家就是说在做的时候一定是这还做到百分之八十的和真实的参考图
做到百分之八十项就可以了啊
就不要去过于纠结每一个小褶皱
但是呢他的受力啊他的呃他的受力
然后他的艺术表现
然后这个地方的话才是大家应该更加的关注的一些地方啊
好
然后最后一个部分呢就是我想给大家呃
呃分享一下就是我的一个呃新做的一些东西啊
所以这两个一些动态
呃看一下这个动态
呃这个这个东西我还在做啊
就这个月比较偷懒啊
我也没有出新的视频
就是本来想出这几套换装的啊
然后这里先给大家分享一下
就是比如说像我们在做一些呃比如大家很关心一些服装的一些动态解算啊
对吧
其实服装的动态也算他不会有太大的一个动和运动
是吧
不会有太大的摆动和一个运动
他的头发
然后会用稍微大一点啊
服装的话大概有一些许的褶皱变化啊
就可以了
嗯
然后这个也是啊
然后这个也是我们的服装啊整体的一个受力的话
我们会先把它的一个静态做好啊
然后通过一遍一遍模拟来进行一个调整
然后来做到一个这样子一个动态的一个效果
然后包括像这里也是啊
啊
这里也是啊
我们先做好了一个他的静态受力对吧
然后我们再进行一个服装解算
他自然就会根据他的动作不同产生不一样的褶皱
对吧
其实说所以说我们的这个受力分析不论是你做动态也好
还是做静态也好啊
都是非常的呃有用的
包括这里也是啊
这里会有一些挤压对吧
稍微暂停一下
然后这里呢也是会有一些挤压
然后这里会有一些腿坠
然后整个毛发会有一些毛发和这个项链就不说了啊
就主要是我们在md里面解算的时候
在初始状态下就一定要
这些挤压这些垂坠
都已经交代清楚
因为我们的衣服其实他
本身
面料之间他是会有一些呃这种受力的受力的情况的
所以说我们在运动的时候其实他走走变化不会特别的
所以说我们在做动态之前就是大家一定要
一定要做好这个一个静态的一个模型啊
从静态模型的话大家如果刚开始做的话也就一定要
一定要就是说理解这个受力啊
然后理解分析对吧
应用
然后这边提升对吧
就是这么一个过程
然后呃关于我这件这这个衣服呃这个衣服的制作流程的话
我大概给大家看一下这也是之前做的
请望找一找
嗯
对
还是这样啊
首先我会去算一下这个md的一个大型
I will do it, right?
Then I will adjust the talent in this place.
It can be adjusted if it is not suitable, right?
Then it goes all the way to the back,
all the way to the back,
and then we will make some detailed adjustments.
You can see here that
I am still adjusting his character.
That is to say, from the beginning to the end,
I will always make adjustments to this character,
because it will affect the
whole clothing.
So I said that this point is still
when everyone is making,
don't stare at your character and don't move.
That is to say, the adjustment still needs to be adjusted,
and here we also adjust some panels
to reduce the movement of this place, right?
I said at this time to reduce the movement of this place,
I will use the龜拔 and then brush this place a little tighter.
If this place is,
you can reduce the movement of this place.
Then here,
we will do some, use some buttons,
because the buttons,
it will have a little bit left,
a little bit,
a little bit of force,
and then here,
we can make a little bit of the force of this piece of panel,
and then we will change the quality of the button a little bit higher,
and then here,
the panel will produce some frills.
These are some deliberately made frills,
that is to say,
it's not that everyone wants to put it on like that.
So when everyone is doing it,
you must deliberately make some frills,
and then how to do it deliberately
is still based on what I said earlier,
such a tree,
such some reference pictures,
such some artistic foundations
to make a production.
Then after I finished the MD part,
you can see this video,
which is half,
such a big half is done in MD,
do it in MD, right?
So MD,
I don't do it fast,
that is to say,
everyone must make the base in MD,
so the things behind it are easier to do,
and then later I will go to ZB,
just simply fix it,
simply fix it,
for example,
some detailed folds,
some fine lines,
I will put these things in ZB,
add a little bit in ZB,
because this thing is actually for it.
A general
ZB comparison, right?
It will be more on the shoulder,
it will be more on the shoulder,
but you have to be clear when you are familiar with it,
that is, when I need it,
this place is more foldable,
so whether you do it from MD or ZB,
you can do it,
you must know what you need,
it is more important than what you will do,
so this place continues to brush,
continue to brush,
and then this place,
I slightly smoothed this place a little bit,
I think this place is too exaggerated,
this fold is a little unscientific,
so I smoothed it a little bit,
these things are all some detailed adjustments,
of course,
in MD,
it is definitely possible to do this,
you can do this,
but it depends on everyone's preferences,
it can be done,
and then I will do it in Blender next,
go into Blender to do some detailed decoration,
detailed decoration,
for example,
do some envelopes,
and then I will do it in ZB,
do some small details,
right?
Then do some,
in fact, the main thing is to do the envelopes,
this envelope, right?
Because I made MD,
my personal production habit is not to make the thickness,
because it makes the thickness,
first of all, its face number will increase by double,
so it will increase too much burden on our computer,
and then the second one, it will be UV, it will overlap,
it is the opposite,
it is not very comfortable when it is on the material,
so I use the method of adding a layer of envelopes,
add a layer of envelopes,
and this way it is better to match its thickness.
Like ordinary clothes,
it will also have envelopes,
so without envelopes,
we create an envelope for it.
Then the problem is not big, right?
So these things are not based on a really realistic one,
a way to consider,
it is based on a production constifty,
to put it bluntly, it is lazy,
if you want to be lazy,
you can do this,
that is to say, everyone is flexible,
go making,
to make your own clothing
and then the thickness of the collar
I should have it on this side
I took a layer by myself
and then squeezed out a layer for it
squeeze out a layer like this
because our MD board is already calculated
right
after calculating
and then directly
put a layer on it
directly put a layer on it
and then we put
for example, here
I look at
this
for example
just make up that feeling
we all do almost
I will put a light
right
put a light
I also hope that the whole picture has a main character
right
then this place is the most dense place
and then this place is also the brightest place
is where I want everyone to go to see
and then my details are all concentrated in a dark area
in fact, his overall idea
and we do this is almost
right
above
bright
but my dense place
is not the same as everyone
my dense place is the main bright place
his dense place is the dark place
right
but the overall idea is the same
is
our bright place
I hope everyone can see
and then the details will be
for example, these details will be concentrated in some dark places
so in general
this is one
why it looks very realistic when it is changed like this
because some of our realistic photo photography techniques
are actually like this
a skill that many big bosses will spend
is also like this
is to put the details in a dark place
in the dark and some gray parts
like these pictures
can also see the details of these patterns
including these details
are actually in a dark part of it
right
including these above
the details are in the dark
it brightens
instead
for example, this place is a
little bit of a detail
like this
but this is different
its details are in the bright part
right
its dark part of the details will be relatively small
so we want to do our own
for example
some of them want to imitate some big brain
some styles
including some art
some processing
must be analyzed in this way
when we are doing clothing
we also deliberately make some
plans for some of the places where the curse exists
and then consider the overall light and shadow relationship
and then finally get some
relatively different art effects
but these two
I feel that although their colors are more similar
but I feel that their styles
are still
just some of the difference
including these
light and shadow
a shape is not the same
ok
and then
and then after I'm done in Blender
after I'm done in Blender
just like I just said
I will do a lot of things like this in this SD
some of these little icons
these things
after we do it
we put it in Blender
and paste it on the map
including these
these feel like a little cat
I didn't do it very carefully
I made some little cat balls
and then I made it into a whole material
and then we mixed it up
and then we gave it to him
and that's about it
you can get one
like this one
work
this work
and then so to speak
my this
look at my this
what do you call this
this one?
I turned this off
and then look at it
this is my whole
costume production idea
this costume production idea
including like this is the same
when this is this
if you do static
and do dynamic
it's actually the same
right
we do the static first
do the static first
and then go to MD
and do some calculations
and then do some calculations
including these are all
all done like this
so we have to do a good job
if you are satisfied with your own good-looking work
then our
subject analysis
and then some of the art styles
and then some of the details of the curse
and then include some of our art-related knowledge
and then include some technical-related knowledge
for example pop
yes
technical-related knowledge
I may talk less about this section
ah
like this
as said in the bulletin
ah
what is this
these four sides
this mesh
and these
uh
ah
for example
what kind of clothes
how thick
these more technical-related problems
may be in this section
I talked about less
but
these questions
really
I highly recommend
you to watch MD official
it's what de
made those videos
video
really
you can think of the problem
ah
Even 99% of them can be solved in you.
That is to say, I hope that everyone will not jump when watching technical videos.
It is necessary to look from beginning to end.
I am also because every time I open a video,
this MD official sent a video,
I will watch it from beginning to end.
It may be a little accelerated,
but I won't jump.
That is to say, you can learn a lot of technical things.
So if you have technical problems,
you can go and watch this MD official video.
Then I mainly want to talk about some theories,
some things about some art,
so that everyone can do it after making their own work,
or say that they can't do it.
For example, like I said at the beginning,
the first two questions,
why did I do it?
I can't do what I want to do to solve such a relatively broad problem.
It's like this.
Okay, then,
I've finished talking about all the content here.
Then the next thing is to give everyone a brief introduction to my own B station.
This is my B station.
I have also made some new things recently and sent them to everyone.
Then this is a computer configuration that I am currently using.
Computer configuration is fine.
I have used one of the 207 graphics cards.
Then,
my B station is a computer configuration.
Then, my B station is a computer configuration.
My B station is a computer configuration.
B station can receive up to 20,000 kW.
Then I will put some of the clothes,
some of the modeling works,
and some of the fast-release,
and some of the experiences I usually have.
I will post it on top.
Then here is my Weibo,
which is also 20,000 kW.
Then this is my B station,
which is not kW.
Then this is my account,
which is also kW.
Then there are these.
And then I recently published a course, which is this, what is this called, Lolita, this course, this is a course that I and Moshengzhi Guangshu, Moshengzhi Guangshu, sent me, a course that Moshengzhi Guangshu sent me,
that is, if you want to know more about the entire production process, if you want to learn some specific historical operations, you can go buy this course and have a look, you can buy this course and have a look, now there are almost 700 people, there are 700 people, and then there are a lot of people in the group who have also done it, so if you come and learn from me, I should be able to do it, and then I will also answer questions for you.
So
the other things must be gone, and then I've been wanting to do an event recently, so I'll offer you a model of such a figure, if there's anything I can do, exposed sides, invented, cook, hair, makeup, characters, skin
, I can do all this, and then everyone can make something like this, and then inside a dynamic one, then fly it up, but it's just an idea. I haven't done this myself, so I don't want to do it.
So you can pay more attention to MD's official videos
and my own Bilibili.
You can pay more attention to it.
There's nothing else.
That's it for me.
Okay, if you have any other questions,
about Mr. Xuefei's courses,
please pay attention to his Bilibili account and Weibo.
Okay, thank you Mr. Xuefei for bringing so much content to us.
We are also very happy to have Mr. Xuefei here.
No problem.
Thank you Mr. Xuefei.
Please say goodbye to Mr. Xuefei.
Okay.
Wait a moment.
It's my turn soon.
Please wait patiently.
You can read the comments.
I will answer the questions in the Q&A section.
I think there are some parts that are not clear,
or some parts that I don't understand.
I will answer them later.
If you have any questions now,
if you want to ask Mr. Xuefei,
you can ask now.
Because my part might be a little long.
Mr. Xuefei doesn't have to be online all the time.
Oh, I see.
I thought there would be a Q&A section at the end.
Oh, no, no, no.
Because my part is a little long.
It doesn't take that long.
Okay, okay.
Are you interested in what Mr. Xuefei said?
Or do you have any questions?
No, I don't think so.
I think it's because Mr. Xuefei said it clearly.
No, no, no.
Maybe I said it too broadly.
I don't think it's easy to understand.
Oh, there is a picture of Bai Ze.
Bai Ze's picture...
I'll send it to...
I'll send it to Sherry.
It's on my Instagram.
Okay.
Or you can post it on your own Bilibili.
So that everyone can see it when they pay attention to you.
Okay.
I'll send it to my Bilibili.
And then what about hair?
How do you do your hair?
The hair is done with the Blender hair model.
Not with XGene.
Because the dynamic model...
It's this hair.
This hair.
Because the dynamic model...
It must be done in a software.
Which one is used.
Right?
If you go to other software and simulate it,
It's going to be very big.
It's about this hair.
When you just go from one software to another software,
It may be tens of thousands.
Plus the simulation,
You get tens of thousands per pin.
Right?
How many pins do I have here?
I might have more than 60 pins here.
There's no way to do this.
There's no way to support it.
So it's done in Blender.
Is the person carved?
The person is carved.
There's a carving part.
Do you have a cloth material rendering tutorial?
If you have a cloth material rendering tutorial,
In this tutorial,
It talks about material rendering.
Then there are some adjustments.
Then there is a production of some fine details.
It's all about it.
It's okay to learn Blender for cloth material rendering.
If you learn Blender,
Actually,
A more mainstream renderer now.
It's still like UE.
If it's real rendering,
Of course,
UE is the best.
Right?
And then there's another one.
It's Ardor.
Maya's Ardor.
Or Max's C4D.
There's Ardor.
But I choose to use Blender for one reason.
One is that it's open source and free.
And then there's another reason.
It's GPU rendering.
It's faster.
Otherwise,
Its rendering effect.
Personally,
In some ways,
It's not as good as Ardor.
But it's fast.
Right?
Fast is a very important thing.
That is to say,
We are working on it.
So as long as we are fast at rendering,
Then our test effect is fast.
The whole production cycle will be shorter.
In this case,
You can keep doing what you want to do.
Instead of doing it in one step.
For example,
I'm going to do a character for a month or two.
Two or three months.
It's very tiring.
If I do this,
Maybe it's just a day or two.
That's about it.
And then the rendering time.
It's very fast.
Then I'll just show you my hair.
Here's the hair.
I'm not going to show it for the time being.
Because if I open a brand file,
I'm still here.
If you connect it,
It's going to be more.
That's the whole file.
I can't pull it all the way.
It's only after rendering.
It's going to look like this.
And then on two platforms.
On the CCTalk platform.
It's a course that Guangshu sent me.
I'm not Guangshu.
A lot of people just put me.
He called me Guangshu.
I'm not Guangshu.
It's a course that Guangshu sent me.
And then the dynamic material is in MD.
Yes, it is.
All the materials in it.
It's all in MD.
Make a resolution.
And these.
These are all in MD.
Resolved.
MD resolution.
I'm anyway.
If you want to do something like this.
It's a simple thing.
Simple things.
I highly recommend that you use MD.
Because I've used a lot of resolution software.
Including Maya's resolution.
Or Blender's resolution.
Or MD.
Or Houdini.
That is to say.
From the point of view of usability and output.
These two points.
If you say that the output is good.
Then the usability will be more difficult.
Right?
So as a point of balance in the middle.
I think MD is a.
For clothing resolution.
A very good entry point for clothing production.
You don't have to worry about it.
After you learn MD.
Let me learn other clothing resolution.
Is MD useless?
No.
These things are all connected.
But.
If you say to enter.
Or start to make try-on clothes.
MD is a very good software.
You can choose MD first.
Then there is another question.
Can it lead to UE?
Of course it can lead to UE.
Because UE supports ABC format.
So it can lead to UE.
Then UE itself.
It has its own physical simulation.
Right?
Also has UE.
It also has its own hair simulation.
Right?
UE has everything.
But its usability.
May be worse than MD.
Because it is a game engine.
It has to take care of a lot of things.
Right?
And its content.
The amount will be particularly large.
You just have a UU5.
How big are people's files?
Right?
You just see a file.
It will take half a day to edit the editor.
Edit for half a day.
Right?
So from the usability point of view.
That is to say.
If you start.
We can start from.
Through.
Like using MD.
Use Blender.
Do it like this.
Right?
Then.
Is MD good or ZB good?
All right.
There is nothing.
A good one.
A bad one.
That is to say.
You want to do it in MD.
Then do it in MD.
You want to go to ZB.
Draw two strokes.
Then you can also go to ZB.
These two things are not conflicted.
All right.
This is Blender simulation.
It is Blender simulation.
That is, I am currently.
The simulation.
Basically all use Blender.
Then MD can import other software.
MD.
The format it exports is still very rich.
Let me show you.
If you export it.
It can export.
Two formats of ABC.
Then this side can export.
Many of these two-layer formats.
Then OBJ.
This kind of sequence.
Although we have not used it.
I used ABC.
But.
Since it supports so many formats.
So in your own software.
It will definitely find.
Find an interface that corresponds to the format.
Then.
So.
It must be able to export.
Right.
If there are no other problems.
That's it.
How to calculate the thickness of the material.
The thickness.
Like I said just now.
I will use some more cheating methods.
To show the thickness of this material.
That is.
If you count again.
In AMD.
I still count it as a single layer.
Because.
MD.
All double layers.
Then you have to do this kind of dynamic.
Right.
Double layer.
If you want to do this kind of dynamic.
His.
This.
The flicker of this model.
Like this.
It's very much.
That is.
In fact,
In return for it.
A decent operation.
Might.
Naturally.
To share the quote.
Just give up his.
Don't be by.
Oh,
actually I sometimes.
My phone will go off.
But you can't listen.
Right.
Yes,
Thanks.
Yes.
Ah,
Ok.
Good.
Yes.
Right.
In too far away.
No,
Yes,
You're welcome.
Okay, we'll end here.
Okay.